Once again, I represent at the top of the LoRaWAN server and at the bottom the IoT platform.
We want to connect them with the MQTT protocol, but this time the broker is not on the LoRaWAN
server, as we've seen before, it's a complete independent entity between the LoRaWAN server and
the IoT platform.
In that case, we need to install and configure it.
Of course, we could use a public MQTT broker and try this configuration, but keep in mind that
if you do so, all datas are public, so please try that only for testing purposes.
Great.
So now same question as before.
Who is the subscriber and who is the publisher?
Let's separate the uplink stream and the downlink stream.
For the uplink stream,
there is one publisher on the LoRaWAN server.
It will publish on the Broker all uplink messages on a specific topic that you can often choose yourself
or at least customize.
And there is one subscriber on the IoT platform.
It's going to receive data of its favorite topic on the broker.
For the downlink stream, there is one publisher on the IoT platform.
It will publish on the broker all downlink messages on a specific topic.
And there is one subscriber on the LoRaWAN server.
It will receive all messages sent by the IoT platform and depending on the topic, the messages will
have a different meaning.